#### Contact

malatorr@indiana.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/mariaa-66aa563b (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Nonprofits

**PCR** 

Research

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

**CPR** 

**BLS** 

**ACLS** 

#### Honors-Awards

Hudson-Holland Scholar

21st Century Scholar

Robert Wood Johnson Foundation Scholar

# Maria A.

Travel RN, BSN

Oakland, California

# Summary

I worked 1.5 years as a progressive care nurse at Eskenazi Health in Indianapolis, and absolutely loved working with the unique patient population of Indianapolis, IN. I am currently on my first travel nurse assignment at Kaiser Permanente, in Oakland, California, and am so excited to be able to live one of my dreams. I wish to become a nurse practitioner and work in international medicine, pairing with non-profit organizations to give under-served patients access to healthcare. I was recently accepted into the Family Nurse Practitioner Graduate Program at Indiana University School of Nursing and will begin in August 2018. I would like to continue to work at a medical facility that serves a diverse patient population and has partnerships with health centers overseas. I am looking for connections in California, Texas, and New York, but am open to opportunities everywhere, especially internationally.

# Experience

Kaiser Permanente Travel Registered Nurse March 2018 - Present (2 years 4 months) Oakland, California

Eskenazi Health IICU RN

June 2016 - March 2018 (1 year 10 months)

Indianapolis, Indiana Area

Provide high quality care to patients from all medical and socioeconomic backgrounds on a 36 bed progressive care unit.

Riley Hospital for Children
Patient Care Intern
January 2015 - May 2016 (1 year 5 months)
Indianapolis, Indiana Area

Assisting nurse with medical and nonmedical procedures, including obtaining vital signs, documenting intake and output, performing baths, providing support for pediatric patients.

#### Camp Kesem IU

Volunteer Counselor September 2010 - August 2014 (4 years)

Camp Kesem is a nonprofit organization that hosts a free weeklong summer camp for children whose parents have or have had counselor. As volunteer counselors, college students organize the week of camp, raise awareness about Camp Kesem, and raise the monetary funds and other donations necessary for camp.

# Timmy Global Health Student Volunteer

September 2010 - August 2014 (4 years)

Timmy Global Health is a nonprofit organization that strives to create sustainable healthcare both locally and globally. College chapters raise awareness about Timmy and global heath, raise funds to send to partner clinics in Guatemala, Ecuador, and the Dominican Republic, and host in-kind donation drives to collect medication and sunscreen for the medical brigades hosted every three months in said clinics.

## IU Simon Cancer Center Summer Research Program

Intern

May 2013 - July 2013 (3 months)

Immunohistochemistry Characterization of Splenic Nodules in Mice Undergoing Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation

#### Indiana University Bloomington

Student Researcher

September 2011 - March 2013 (1 year 7 months)

Perform PCR mutagenesis on the Huntingtin-Interacting Protein, hip1, to study the interaction between the huntingtin gene and its binding proteins.

# IU Simon Cancer Center Summer Research Program

Intern

May 2011 - July 2011 (3 months)

IU Simon Cancer Center Summer Research Program, Indianapolis, Indiana, Summer, 2011

Worked for 8 weeks, 40 hours weekly

Research included developing a microsomal assay to characterize the metabolism of S-mephenytoin by CYP2C19

Veteran Affairs Medical Center Microbiology Lab Volunteer April 2010 - August 2010 (5 months)

Volunteered for eight weeks, 16 hours weekly

Mostly clerical and organizing paper work, also cultured Staph bacteria
samples from patients

Project SEED, Veteran Affairs Medical Center Intern April 2009 - July 2009 (4 months)

Worked for 8 weeks, 40 hours weekly

Research included using human embryonic kidney cells to study the effects of over expressing h-NMNAT 2 in cancer cells

## Education

Indiana University School of Nursing BSN, Nursing, Nursing · (2014 - 2016)

Indiana University Bloomington
Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Biology, General · (2010 - 2014)

Arsenal Technical High School
Academic Honors, Math/Science Magnet · (2006 - 2010)